<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<gamebook>
    <items>
        <item id="1" type="apparel" attr="luck" value="2">Keeper's horn</item>
        <item id="2" type="miscellaneous">Golden claw</item>
        <item id="3" type="weapon" attr="agi" value="2">Steel sword</item>
        <item id="4" type="armor" attr="vit" value="3">Studded helmet</item>
        <item id="5" type="apparel" attr="luck" value="1">Talisman of luck</item>
        <item id="6" type="miscellaneous">Emerald</item>
        <item id="7" type="miscellaneous">Gold</item>
        <item id="8" type="weapon" attr="agi" value="3">Mace</item>
        <item id="9" type="miscellaneous">Golden key</item>
    </items>
    <creatures>
        <creature id="1" agi="9" vit="10">Troll</creature>
        <creature id="2" agi="10" vit="8">Ogre</creature>
        <creature id="3" agi="11" vit="9">Dungeon guard</creature>
        <creature id="4" agi="10" vit="6">Wolf</creature>
        <creature id="5" agi="8" vit="5">Mercenaries</creature>
    </creatures>
    <paragraph id="0" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            Hey, Daredevil! It is about you say, that in your veins flows ice-cold water
            and your muscles are made from finest steel.
            If so, look into the sunset. There at the border of Almanhagor Kingdom begins unexplored dungeon.
            Only you can discover its Great Secret.
            Good luck!
        </text>
        <path>1</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="1" type="normal">
        <text>
            Entrance to the dungeons is wide, overgrown with grass and lush bushes.
            You rearrange your clothes and equipment. Light the lantern!
            You are entering the corridor. It is high, so you don't have to stoop.
            It leads you straight to the north. Soon you reach the T shaped crossroad.
            Its branches leads to the west, east and south. From where you came.
            There is also an old man sitting on the rock. He open his mouth with difficulty and says
            that you should go west, and then take few right turns and you will reach your goal.
            Will you listen to him and go west? If yes, swipe right.
            Otherwise go east and, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">2</path>
            <path swipe="left">3</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="2" type="normal">
        <text>
            You are walking forward. It is so dark that you can't even see what is in front of you.
            But you are brave, you would not be scared by the darkness or strange noises around.
            For some reason you feel anxiety. Wait! There are doors on your right.
            Are you willing to open them? Swipe right.
            If you want to go further, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">4</path>
            <path swipe="left">5</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="3" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            So you decided not to listen the old fool and go east. Your each step echo against the walls.
            But you walk confident, because you see some light at the end of a hallway.
            You cannot wait to see what is there. There is also some strange noise coming from the front.
            It sounds like a mad man laugh.
        </text>
        <path>6</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="4" type="normal">
        <text>
            The doors are not looking solid. You catch the handle of the door.
            And you try to open them. But they won't even move, so you began to pull the handle harder.
            You can't open them, they are locked.
            If you would like to break them down, swipe right.
            And if would you like to continue walking along the hallway, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">7</path>
            <path swipe="left">5</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="5" type="normal">
        <text>
            You are wondering just few steps further and the hallway turns right to the north.
            Just another black hole in front of you. It feels like you are just going nowhere.
            You took a few steps more and realized that something stinks over here.
            It smells like a dead rat and pair of old sweaty stockings mixed together.
            You cover your mouth and discover that you can go right by, swiping right.
            Or go forward by, swiping left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">8</path>
            <path swipe="left">9</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="6" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You got yourself a little bit closer to the source of the noise.
            You notice a half naked man chained to the walls. A man was almost hanging from that wall,
            but he seemed happy. He noticed you and begun to speak.
            Hello stranger! What a lovely sunny day we have. Look at those beautiful birds flying on the horizon...
            Oh, excuse me sir. Where are my manners.. Are you thirsty my lord?
            Please take some of this water and drink with me. You will not regret it.
            He is clearly out of his mind, but he is pointing towards the light source with his head.
            You are anxious of the mystery behind this, so you decided to go towards the light source.
        </text>
        <path>10</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="7" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You took a momentum and smashed the door. As I told you, they weren't solid and
            you broke them to many wooden pieces. You immediately heard that something is snoring loudly.
            It was dark inside so you picked up your lantern and you noticed big shaggy and stinky troll
            laying in the corner of the chamber you have entered. You were lucky that he didn't woke up
            while you broke through the doors.
        </text>
        <path>11</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="8" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            And so you walked into some chamber. The stink has become more intense.
            Your lantern discovers the chamber and its content. It turns out that big shaggy troll
            is just laying in the corner sleeping and snoring.
        </text>
        <path>11</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="9" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            And so you go forward through the darkness where your lantern is your only guide.
            It is all quiet. You can only hear your own steps. And so you walk and walk.
            But suddenly silence was interrupt by the sound of breaking string.
            After that you have heard loud knocking above you.
            You have to check your luck to see what is going to happen next.
        </text>
        <luckypath>12</luckypath>
        <unluckypath>13</unluckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="10" type="crossroad">
        <text>
            And so you have entered a chamber. It was surprisingly lit and peaceful.
            In the center of the room there was a fountain of a fat goblin size.
            You can only hear the sound of the falling water.
            You took few more steps towards the fountain.
            Hello there, my friend. You head someone saying. But all you can see is just some doors
            to the north, and heading west. Who is that? You asked.
            I am here. He answered and you noticed some person abut against the wall.
            Go, drink some of this water with me, and let's have a talk. He proposed.
            If you trust him, swipe right, and take some water.
            Otherwise try to attack him by, swiping down.
            There is also a possibility of leaving this chamber using northern doors, by swiping up,
            or using western doors by, swiping left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">16</path>
            <path swipe="down">15</path>
            <path swipe="up">18</path>
            <path swipe="left">17</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="11" type="normal">
        <text>
            You have noticed that that troll is holding something shining in his hands.
            If would like to take it, swipe right.
            But if just want to go further, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">19</path>
            <path swipe="left">20</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="12" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            The knocking was getting louder and louder, but you decided to go few steps forward.
            At this moment dozen of cannon balls dropped from above. But you were lucky and nothing happened to you.
            For sure it was a trap, but that gave you a feeling that you are walking in good direction.
        </text>
        <path>14</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="13" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            The knocking was getting louder and louder, but you didn't really know what to do.
            Something just hit you from the back. It was such an impact that you fell to the ground and lost consciousness...
            You woke up a moment later and realized it was some sort of trap.
            Because of the damage you lost four of you vitality.
        </text>
        <path>14</path>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">-4</effect>
        </effects>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="14" type="crossroad">
        <text>
            And so you went further and got to the crossroad, and three paths has appeared.
            All of the paths were looking exactly the same and so you got confused about which to choose.
            You can choose to go east by, swiping right.
            Or you can go north by, swiping up.
            But also you can go west by swiping left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">21</path>
            <path swipe="up">22</path>
            <path swipe="left">23</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="15" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            So you decided to attack. You have drawn your sword and immediately rushed toward the enemy.
            It took you about 2 seconds to reach your target, but that strange person didn't ever moved
            a bit. You have swang your sword. And the character disappeared, so you just hit the air.
            After that a strange voice said. You will regret it!
        </text>
        <path>24</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="16" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You have leaned towards fountain and you got some water in your hands.
            It was simply pure. You took a sip. You felt like it was the tastiest water you have ever drunk.
            It was very refreshing and for sure it was enchanted. You have gain two points of vitality.
        </text>
        <path>26</path>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">2</effect>
        </effects>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="17" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You have grabbed a handle of the doors and opened them.
            A narrow corridor lays ahead of you. The way is lit by the torches hanging on the walls.
            It has to lead somewhere! And so you walk and the corridor turns right,
            and just after the turn stairway to the lower level of the dungeon begins.
            While you are descending down the stairs, you notice that they are made of stone.
            They were probably made by the old dwarves, in the times when they were
            working hard, just digging deeper to find some treasures, or to seek legendary adventures.
            Nowadays, I don't know any dwarf that would move his fat belly further than 100 feets from
            his kitchen or garden.
            But let's back to the story. You have just reached lower level of the dungeon.
            In front of you lays dwarven mining corridor.
            Unfortunately corridors walls aren't equipped with torches any more.
            Your surrounding is enveloped into darkness. But you are brave and you go forward.
            You are beginning to see the end of the tunnel and you hear the howling dragon.
            It was so terrifying that you have goose pimples.
            You left the corridor and found yourself in some giant rift.
        </text>
        <path>27</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="18" type="crossroad">
        <text>
            Your way is to the north. You have opened the door and entered a tunnel that leads you to
            another chamber. The doorplate says that this is armory. So you open doors slowly
            expecting someone to be inside it. But there is no one inside.
            Your torch lit up the armory. You can see that fine swords are hanging on the eastern wall of the chamber.
            On the western wall there are many armor parts like helmets, boots, chainmails, shields.
            In the middle of the armory you have found special stand with a golden claw
            and talisman on it.
            You can choose one item from the armory.
            To take the golden claw, swipe right.
            If you want to take the talisman, swipe left.
            If you choose to take sword with you, swipe up.
            And if you would like to equip yourself with helmet, swipe down.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">28</path>
            <path swipe="left">29</path>
            <path swipe="up">30</path>
            <path swipe="down">31</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="19" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            You are carefully and quietly moving towards the troll.
            The item in his hand is an emerald. The prettiest thing you have ever seen.
            You have leaned and tried to slowly take away the shining treasure from the hands of the stinky troll.
            You have to check your luck in order to find out if you will succeed or fail.
        </text>
        <luckypath>32</luckypath>
        <unluckypath>33</unluckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="20" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You decided not to disturb the troll's dream and go further using the northern doors.
            You have opened them quietly and entered another dark corridor.
        </text>
        <path>34</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="21" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You have gone east and a moment later, entered a dark chamber.
        </text>
        <path>35</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="22" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You path leads to the north. It feels like its is getting colder with each step.
            You see a bridge in front of you. But what is it for? Is there some river?
            You can't hear any water flow. You take some steps forward and realize that the bridge is not meant to cross the river.
            It is meant to cross a giant rift which starts from west and ends far to the east.
            The rift is about forty meters hight and about 10 meters wide.
            You can also observe some lights on its bottom.
            You have crossed a bridge and found yourself just in front of a steel doors with
            a sentence, come and play with us, scratched on it.
            You have pushed the door and hardly opened them, because of their weight.
        </text>
        <path>36</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="23" type="end">
        <text>
            You took a path to the west. Is getting windy inside this corridor.
            Fire revels on your torch and gives you no view of what is laying in front of you.
            The wind is getting stronger and stronger as you go towards east.
            Finally your torch went out. You don't have anything around you to light it.
            But you decided to go few steps more.
            In absolute darkness you didn't realized that the floor has ended.
            You have slipped and fall into endless rift...
            I am sorry, but this is the end of your adventure.
        </text>
        <end>loss</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="24" type="normal">
        <text>
            Well... that was wierd. You are astonished of that have happened.
            It was a fine swing of a sword, and he just turned to smoke and disappeared.
            All you think about now is to get away from this mysterious chamber.
            You can walk out thought the north doors by, swiping right.
            Or use the western doors by, swiping left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">18</path>
            <path swipe="left">25</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="25" type="end">
        <text>
            You have approached the western doors. They are not locked so you open them and walk into corridor.
            It is lit with torches hanging on the walls. This way has to lead to some treasure...
            Suddenly you felt something cold on your wrist. You have dropped you sword.
            It turned out that you were caught in the trap with you hand shackled.
            You began to thrash, but it was useless. Some hidden doors opened on the left side of yours
            and you were dragged inside... I told you that you will regret it. A familiar voice you heard.
            Now you spend rest of your live in this damp and dark prison of mine.
            You shall never attack the keeper of the dungeon...
            Unfortunately this is the end of you adventure.
        </text>
        <end>loss</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="26" type="itempick">
        <text>
            Now you feel much stronger, so you walk towards the mysterious person...
            Come and sit with me. He said.
            You have sat on the left side...
            So you are the one they call a daredevil. He continuous.
            Well... I see you were not possessed by the power of that water.
            I am sure you have seen just a minute ago what it can do with those weak minds.
            I don't want to stop you anymore, I know what your goal is.
            Just let me give you this little horn, which I hope will help you in your way.
            And also I want to give you some advice...
            If you want to reach your goal without any further interrupts, pick the western doors...
            Ok it is my time to go. He said, stood up quickly and left the chamber using the western doors.
            The horn he gave you gives you two points of luck.
        </text>
        <item>1</item>
        <path>37</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="27" type="normal">
        <text>
            The dragon you heard is just sitting above on the top of the rift.
            So you hid against the wall.
            You can see some bridge above it to the west, but it seems like there is no sense of going towards that direction.
            Moreover it turns out that the way you came here is closed now with some steel gate.
            You can now choose corridor in front of you which looks like being second part of the one
            you have just walked through, by swiping left.
            Or you can continue walking to the eastern side of the rift by, swiping right,
            it looks like it is turning north some fifty meters from just position.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">38</path>
            <path swipe="left">39</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="28" type="itempick">
        <text>
            You have reached your arm for this fine little piece of gold.
            Finally your adventure starts to pay off. You have put your little treasure in your bag
            and left the armory using northern door, thinking that much more valuable treasure is just ahead of you.
        </text>
        <item>2</item>
        <path>40</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="29" type="itempick">
        <text>
            So you decided to pick some fine steel sword from this armory.
            This little masterpiece of a craft will make you more dangerous during fights.
            It gives you two points of agility while you bear it.
            And so you leave the chamber using the northern door, with a new sword in your hand.
        </text>
        <item>3</item>
        <path>40</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="30" type="itempick">
        <text>
            So you are the one that care more about the defence, than about the attack.
            You picked up a studded helmet and placed it on your head.
            It feels lite while you move, but hard so it will protect you.
            And so you leave the chamber using the northern door.
        </text>
        <item>4</item>
        <path>40</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="31" type="itempick">
        <text>
            So you took the talisman to your hands. It was made from mammoth bone pieces and many trinkets.
            The talisman is enchanted. It gives you a point of a luck.
        </text>
        <item>5</item>
        <path>40</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="32" type="itempick">
        <text>
            He is not holding it hard so you slowly took it away. The shining treasure is yours.
            The troll have gasped loudly and shifted to his right back.
            Congratulations! You succeeded! Let's hope he will not find out who has stolen his precious.
        </text>
        <item>6</item>
        <path>41</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="33" type="fight">
        <text>
            He is not holding it hard so you slowly took it away. The shining treasure is yours.
            But you are a crock and you drop the emerald on the ground.
            Troll has immediately woke up, took his club and swung it towards you.
            But you dodge and received no damage...
            There is no way to escape. You have to face the giant troll.
        </text>
        <creature>1</creature>
        <path>42</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="34" type="food">
        <text>
            You are now walking north. The corridor is dark and you cannot see any light in front of you.
            It is good time to eat some food, swipe up. But if you want to just continue walking, swipe right.
        </text>
        <path>35</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="35" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            You have entered a completely dark chamber. It seems that nothing interesting can be found here.
            But you will try your luck. Maybe you will find something useful.
        </text>
        <luckypath>43</luckypath>
        <unluckypath>44</unluckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="36" type="dicegame">
        <text>
            You have entered the chamber, but you could not see anything, because something lights the eyes.
            Suddenly you felt a blow to the back of your head, and you lost consciousness...
            You woke up handcuffed. The chamber was filled with dwarves. All the them chamber were staring at you.
            Finally one of them, who I think is their leader, began to speak...
            All of you! Look! He woke up! ... Who are you? ... It does not matter.
            You have disturbed our peaceful chamber, you filthy creature. What should we do with you?
            He asked the crowd... Let him play the spear throwing! ... and so you will play.
            You have to throw a single spear into the target.
            If you will roll one or two, it means that you missed the target and you lose.
            If you will roll three, four, or five, it means that you hit a target and
            you will be let free to continue your adventure.
            But if you will roll six, it means that you hit the central point of the target and
            you will be let free and receive a gift, because as I heard, no one really did that before.
            The only problem is that you are still handcuffed and you have to hit the target which is
            within thirty meters.
        </text>
        <ranges>
            <range from="1" to="2">48</range>
            <range from="3" to="5">49</range>
            <range from="6" to="6">50</range>
        </ranges>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="37" type="normal">
        <text>
            So what is your decision. Do you want to leave the chamber using the western doors, swipe left,
            or the northern one, swipe right.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">18</path>
            <path swipe="left">17</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="38" type="food">
        <text>
            You are now sneaking by the walls of the rift, so this might dragon will not notice you.
            Your steps are confident and quiet. You simply bypassed the dragon and lead yourself north.
            It is good time to eat some food by, swiping up,
            or if you would like to continue, swipe right.
        </text>
        <path>51</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="39" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You are passing the rift by going north. It seems that it is some king of cave.
            It is dark so you can't see its end. But you continue to walk and
            you take each of your steps carefully and quietly...
            It turns out it is the dead end. You have nowhere to go.
            You have laid your sword and began to think what to do next.
            And so you leaned against the eastern wall... And you felt on your back that the wall
            began to move to your right. You jumped away of the wall.
            The new corridor opened to you. It has to be some secret passage.
            You have picked up your sword and entered the corridor.
            You can see some person standing in front of you.
            He is facing north equipped with fine heavy steel armor and wielding his two hand sword.
            You will have to face him to go further.
        </text>
        <path>52</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="40" type="normal">
        <text>
            You have left the armory and just next to it there is another chamber.
            The doors are opened and you can see someone laughing.
            You have entered the chamber and it was adorned with trophies.
            On the western wall you can see some boar's heads.
            On the eastern wall there is a troll's head and mammoth's head.
            In the northern part of the chamber just by the doors three people sits by the table and drink some ale.
            They seems to be some soldiers. They notice you and say.
            Hello traveler! I am sorry but you have to pay to pass this doors. It costs 10 pieces of gold...
            You don't have any gold with you, but maybe they will accept some trinket.
            If you have a golden claw, you can try to offer it for passage by, swiping right.
            But if you don't want to pay them, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right" require="2">53</path>
            <path swipe="left">54</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="41" type="normal">
        <text>
            Now you can decide whether you want to go west by, swiping left.
            Or you can go north by, swiping right.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">34</path>
            <path swipe="left">55</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="42" type="itempick">
        <text>
            You have defeated the troll and took his emerald.
            It was a hard fight.
        </text>
        <item>6</item>
        <path>41</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="43" type="itempick">
        <text>
            You have found opened chest. You looked inside and found a letter and a mace.
            This mace is a fine piece of a weapon which gives three points of agility.
            The letter was presenting some map, which you think is describing part of the dungeon that you are in.
            The map says that if you will go north you fill find yourself in another chamber.
            Then you should go east and you will find treasure there...
            You have put the treasure in your pocket.
        </text>
        <item>8</item>
        <path>58</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="44" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            Unfortunately you haven't found anything useful. There were just bones, used torches and
            pieces of leather.
        </text>
        <path>58</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="45" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            You are walking north and you can see that a broken bridge is ahead of you.
            Below it there is a quite deep rift which is going from west to far east.
            But you observe that the hole in the bridge isn't that big and you can try to jump over it.
            You have to try your luck to jump over the hole in the bridge.
        </text>
        <luckypath>46</luckypath>
        <unluckypath>47</unluckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="46" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You took a long run and you jumped as far as you can. It was risky, but you succeeded!
            Now you are on the other side of the rift. You rearrange you cloths and equipment once again.
            What else there is to do like not to continue your adventure to the north.
            The corridor was long, but you were able to see the gate lit with torches at the end of it...
            You reached the gate and was looking for a way to open it.
            Finally you found a lever on the you left and you pulled it.
            Gated began to rise slowly.
        </text>
        <path>56</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="47" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You took a long run and you jumped as far as you can... But unfortunately it was not enough.
            You reached the edge of the other side of the bridge, but you slipped and fall to the bottom of rift
            and lost conscious... You woke up a bit letter. You are hurt.
            Lost four points of vitality and two points of luck...
            You have put yourself together. Suddenly you heard dragon howl.
            It was so terrifying that you have goose pimples.
            But you have no other way just to go east towards the howl source, because there
            is nothing on western side of the rift.
        </text>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">-4</effect>
            <effect attr="luck">-2</effect>
        </effects>
        <path>27</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="48" type="end">
        <text>
            You took a spear in your hands it was heavy and distorted, but you had no choice,
            you had to take a swing and throw the spear towards target...
            But you failed, the spear dabbed a target and landed next to it.
            And so you lost... They took you, you were trying to resist, so they stunned you.
            You found yourself locked in some cage, wearing just a tunic. All your equipment was taken away...
            That's the end of your adventure.
        </text>
        <end>loss</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="49" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You took a spear in your hands it was heavy and distorted, but you had no choice,
            you had to take a swing and throw the spear towards target...
            And you succeeded! It was quite a good throw, but you didn't hit the center.
            Two well built man grabbed you under the arms and throw out the chamber using the northern door.
            The leader appeared in th doorway, throw you some key to the ground, and said...
            As we promised you, you are now free to go, but don't you ever dare to come back here,
            because we will not let you free next time. Take this key and unlock your chains...
            The door smashed after them. You took a key and unlocked yourself.
        </text>
        <path>57</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="50" type="itempick">
        <text>
            You took a spear in your hands it was heavy and distorted, but you had no choice,
            you had to take a swing and throw the spear towards target...
            It was perfect! You hit the center of the target!
            There was an absolute silence... And the leader broke it by saying.
            Look! He is the first one to accomplish it! Well done traveler.
            You will be rewarded him with our golden key!..
            Your chains were removed and you are free to go.
            You left the chamber using the northern door. You were given your equipment back.
        </text>
        <item>9</item>
        <path>57</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="51" type="normal">
        <text>
            You have entered some cave which leads you to the north.
            The image of the cave makes you suspicions and feel lack of self-confidence.
            There are many bones and meat pieces all over this place.
            You observed that there are a doors at the end of this room.
            You want to leave this place as fast as you can, you are moving faster, you are almost running towards the doors...
            And suddenly an ogre appeared in front of you, terrifyingly screaming.
            He is about three meters high and has a scar across his chest.
            Ogre are know to be very slow, so you can try to somehow bypass him and avoid combat.
            You have to decide whether you want to fight, swipe left.
            Or try to escape towards the northern doors, swipe right.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">60</path>
            <path swipe="left">61</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="52" type="normal">
        <text>
            He has to be some guard on the duty, he is guarding the treasure for sure.
            He turned his face towards you and began to speak.
            Who are you traveler? You want to get to the treasure. Huh?
            You will have to defeat me first to pass this northern doors.
            I cannot let anyone in, unless I will be presented horn of the keeper,
            but I heard it is just a fable...
            If you have keeper's horn with you, swipe right, and show it to the guard.
            Otherwise you will have to fight with him, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right" require="1">64</path>
            <path swipe="left">63</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="53" type="itemloss">
        <text>
            You took out the golden claw from your bag and show it to them.
            They looked at it curiously, and began to talk to each other...
            After a moment one of them said.
            Ok. That will be enough to pass...
            They opened the doors and let you through saying.
            Never come here again adventurer, or we will make one trophy from your head...
            And they began to laugh. They shut the doors behind you.
        </text>
        <item>2</item>
        <path>65</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="54" type="normal">
        <text>
            You told them that you are not willing to pay, and they should let you through.
            They stood up from their chairs with hate...
            No one pass this chamber for free, my friend.
            It seems that there is no other way than to fight or give them something valuable.
            You can offer them golden claw, if you have it by, swiping right.
            Or you will began to fight by, swiping left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right" require="2">53</path>
            <path swipe="left">66</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="55" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You leave the chamber using western door. The corridor you have entered turns right.
        </text>
        <path>14</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="56" type="fight">
        <text>
            Behind the gate you meet a giant gray wolf. It is growling and barking at you.
            There is nowhere to escape, you have to fight.
        </text>
        <path>67</path>
        <creature>4</creature>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="57" type="normal">
        <text>
            You adventure continues to the north. The corridor is long and lit with torches on both left and right wall.
            It is surprisingly empty here. No doors, no chamber near, no creatures ahead.
            So you continue walking forward. The journey seems to take ages..
            Suddenly you heard a whiz of an arrow. You looked behind you and array just flew past your face.
            Someone is chasing you. You decided to escape...
            You are running as fast as you can to the north.
            From time to time you can hear some arrow heading you, but you are lucky and non of them hits you.
            You turn your head backward again, but you can't see anyone...
            The corridor turns to the east. There is silence for a moment, and then you can hear a bow being drawn.
            Again you looked over your shoulder, and this time you noticed a person wearing black light armor.
            His face is covered by black mask.
            This time he hits you. An arrow gazed your hip and you loose one point of a vitality...
            You are running further and you notice a door on your right side.
            You have to decide quickly whether you want to open them and go inside, swipe right.
            Or you want to continue to run forward, swipe left.
        </text>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">-1</effect>
        </effects>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">68</path>
            <path swipe="left">69</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="58" type="normal">
        <text>
            Now you can leave the chamber using eastern door by, swiping right.
            Or you can use the door leading north, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">59</path>
            <path swipe="left">45</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="59" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You left the chamber using the eastern door. The corridor you have entered turn left.
            Just few meters later it turns right.
            Suddenly you hear a howl of a dragon, you grab your sword and continue to walk forward.
            You are thinking about how such beast could live in the place like that.
            Finally you reach him. His scales are red, and he is about six meters high.
            He is carrying a bag on his left wing.
        </text>
        <path>70</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="60" type="fight">
        <text>
            You decided to face this mighty, but stupid creature.
            The ogre shouts and dashes towards you.
        </text>
        <path>62</path>
        <creature>2</creature>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="61" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            You are trying to dodge his attacks and pass him to get to the doors behind him.
            You have to try your luck if you want to escape the fight.
        </text>
        <unluckypath>71</unluckypath>
        <luckypath>72</luckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="62" type="food">
        <text>
            You have entered a corridor which will lead you to the crossroad.
            I think it is good time to eat some food and regenerate.
            If you wish to do so, swipe up.
            Otherwise continue your adventure by, swiping right.
        </text>
        <path>73</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="63" type="fight">
        <text>
            You decided to fight with the guard. You have drawn your sword and set your fighting stance.
            The guard rises his sword and waits for you to attack. That is going to be a hard fight.
        </text>
        <path>85</path>
        <creature>3</creature>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="64" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You have opened the northern doors of the chamber. On the other side of the doors
            new chamber begins.
        </text>
        <path>75</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="65" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You turned towards north and suddenly you noticed a dragon few meters in front of you.
            His scales are red, and he is about six meters high.
            He is carrying a bag on his left wing.
        </text>
        <path>70</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="66" type="fight">
        <text>
            They have drawn they weapons and began to move towards you.
            You are going to fight against them, but they will be treated as a single enemy.
        </text>
        <creature>5</creature>
        <path>65</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="67" type="normal">
        <text>
            It was a touch fight. You left the chamber using the eastern door.
            You found yourself just next to the crossroad.
            One of the paths leads you to the east, to a corridor which ends with another doors.
            And one heading north...
            If you want to go east, swipe right.
            Otherwise, swipe left
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">75</path>
            <path swipe="left">76</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="68" type="crossroad">
        <text>
            You pulled the handle, but the doors are closed.
            You decided to break them... Another corridor opened for you.
            You take a few steps more and gate falls from the ceiling and blocks the path to the north.
            You are safe now. There is no way that someone will pass these doors...
            It was a good idea to choose this path, but breaking a doors wounds you and
            you lose one point of a vitality.
            There is a crossroad in front of you.
            You can go east, where a dark and endless corridor guides, swipe right.
            You can also continue your way to the south, where you can see some doors, swipe up.
            There is also a possibility to go west, swipe left.
            The hallway to the left is lit with torches and turns left.
        </text>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">-1</effect>
        </effects>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">77</path>
            <path swipe="up">75</path>
            <path swipe="left">78</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="69" type="end">
        <text>
            You are still running as fast you can towards the east.
            Another arrow flew towards you, but this time it hits you in te shoulder.
            The impact was so heavy and pain so server that you almost fell to the ground,
            but you put yourself together...
            You don't know if the corridor was so long or it was because of pain you feel,
            but the path seemed to be endless...
            Finally there is the wall. There is no way to the left or to the right.
            It is the dead end.
            Suddenly you felt cold coming from your back...
            Thats the end of you adventure, traveler.
        </text>
        <end>loss</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="70" type="crossroad">
        <text>
            You took a few steps towards the dragon. He sits on the edge of the rift, looking towards its bottom.
            He has noticed you and turned back. You are preparing yourself to fight...
            But the dragon has spoken. What are you doing here stranger?
            You have lowered your guard. It seems that he is not dangerous.
            You have told him that you are looking for a treasure. And that you want to get to the
            other side of this giant rift.
            He told you that he is living here many years and he has never heard of any treasure hidden in this dungeon.
            He also offered you a help. He can get you to the other side, if you will pay him.
            If you have an emerald with you, swipe right.
            If you have a golden claw, swipe left.
            Otherwise, swipe up.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right" require="6">81</path>
            <path swipe="left" require="2">81</path>
            <path swipe="up">83</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="71" type="fight">
        <text>
            You can see a narrow path on the right side of the ogre.
            You have begun to run towards that direction and you found yourself just next to him.
            Well... you didn't make it. Ogre grabbed you and thrust you back to the enterence of the cave.
            You have to face the might ogre now.
        </text>
        <creature>2</creature>
        <path>62</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="72" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You can see a narrow path on the right side of the ogre.
            You have begun to run towards that direction and you found yourself just next to him.
            And you were successful. This dumb creature wasn't able to react while you were moving so fast.
            You opened the doors and shut them behind you...
            The beast was broke the door and was trying to reach you with his giant hand,
            but you were already to far for him to reach.
        </text>
        <path>62</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="73" type="normal">
        <text>
            You feel a little tired of all this adventure, but you put yourself together and continue your journey.
            You can now go east, using the hallway by, swiping right.
            Or you can open the wooden door on your left, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">77</path>
            <path swipe="left">75</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="74" type="end">
        <text>
            You have entered the another chamber. It is lit with kerosene lamps.
            There are meany ornaments and trophies hanging on the wall.
            Some golden, silver and bone necklaces are placed on the shelf on the western wall.
            There is also a dragon's head trophy on the northern wall.
            The floor is lined with marble slabs.
            But what is most important is that a giant, wooden and silver, engraved chest is placed
            in the middle of a chamber. The text engraved on the chest says, My legacy...
            There is also a man sitting on it. You already know him. He is the man from the fountain chamber.
            He stood up and began to speak...
            The first time I met you I knew you were the one who should obtain this treasure.
            These treasure, like all of the things here, belonged to the creator of these dungeon.
            He died many years ago, but he has not had any heir, so in his last words he said to
            me, that he wants to be buried here in this dungeon, in this chamber, and I should protect his
            riches from the unworthy foes. But he also told me to give it to someone who truly
            deserves it. And here you are now, you have passed many obstacles to get here and
            I think you are the one who deserves it at most...
            He opened a chest and you took a few steps towards it.
            You have leaned over the chest. The things you saw inside made you have opened your mouth wide with astonishment.
            But I won't tell you adventurer what was inside...
            It is up to you to imagine what is inside.
        </text>
        <end>win</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="75" type="end">
        <text>
            You have entered the another chamber. It is lit with kerosene lamps.
            There are meany ornaments and trophies hanging on the wall.
            Some golden, silver and bone necklaces are placed on the shelf on the western wall.
            There is also a dragon's head trophy on the northern wall.
            The floor is lined with marble slabs.
            But what is most important is that a giant, wooden and silver, engraved chest is placed
            in the middle of a chamber. The text engraved on the chest says, My legacy...
            There is also a man sitting on it. He stood up and began to speak...
            Welcome daredevil. You have stood against many trials to reach this chamber.
            These treasure here, like all of the things here, belonged to the creator of these dungeon.
            He died many years ago, but he has not had any heir, so in his last words he said to
            me, that he wants to be buried here in this dungeon, in this chamber, and I should protect his
            riches from the unworthy foes. But he also told me to give it to someone who truly
            deserves it. And here you are now, you have passed many obstacles to get here and
            I think you are the one who deserves it at most...
            He opened a chest and you took a few steps towards it.
            You have leaned over the chest. The things you saw inside made you have opened your mouth wide with astonishment.
            But I won't tell you adventurer what was inside...
            It is up to you to imagine what is inside.
        </text>
        <end>win</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="76" type="normal">
        <text>
            You chose to go north. The corridor is short and immediately turns east.
            There is nothing really here, just a rough walls around you.
            But you have reached another crossing.
            This time you can enter some chamber on the right by, swiping right.
            Or you can continue your path towards east, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">75</path>
            <path swipe="left">77</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="77" type="end">
        <text>
            The path continues to the east. You also notice a light source coming from the ceiling
            at the end of a corridor. You began to dash towards that direction.
            And found a leader which leads you up.
            You have climbed up and found yourself outside of the dungeon.
            You can see endless plain in front of you covered with grain.
            Its is for sure not the path you should take.
            You have turned back to get back to the dungeon.
            But there were no hole by which you left.
            There is just a solid rock. You began to kick it, push it, and even pull it, but it was useless...
            I am sorry adventurer, but your journey is over, you can't go back to the dungeon, but you were so close to the treasure.
        </text>
        <end>loss</end>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="78" type="normal">
        <text>
            The path to the west leads you to the turning to the south.
            You take a few steps more and you are at another crossing.
            You can go west through the gate, swipe right.
            Or you can open the doors on the east, swipe left.
        </text>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="right">56</path>
            <path swipe="left">75</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="80" type="normal">
        <text>
            You were unlucky and the dragon threw you from his back during a flight and you have fallen to the bottom of the rift.
            You lost four points of vitality, because of the damage you have taken.
            Now it is for you to decide whether you want to go to the west, swipe left,
            where you can see some cave begins, and leads to the north.
            Or you can go east, swipe right, where another cave begins and also leads to the north.
        </text>
        <effects>
            <effect attr="vit">-4</effect>
        </effects>
        <paths>
            <path swipe="left">39</path>
            <path swipe="right">51</path>
        </paths>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="81" type="checkluck">
        <text>
            Let it be traveler, let it be. I will take you to the other side of the rift. Said the dragon.
            He put your gift to his bag, and let you sit on his back.
            You can feel that seems to be weak, maybe he is to old, and he lacks his old strength.
            You have to try your luck to see if a dragon will get you to the other side.
            The dragon spread his wings and soar into the air.
        </text>
        <luckypath>82</luckypath>
        <unluckypath>80</unluckypath>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="82" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            The dragon did it. He got you safely to the other side of the rift.
            You came down from his back and thank him you a ride.
            Farewell traveler! He said turning his head and leaned towards the bottom of the rift.
            You are now seeing some doors to the chamber.
            You opened them and saw a man armed with fine steel armor and giant sword.
        </text>
        <path>52</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="83" type="singlepath">
        <text>
            You don't have anything to pay for a flight, so you began to persuade the dragon.
            But it was useless, he told you that he will not do anything for free.
            You had no choice so you made a mad decision. You jumped on the dragon's back.
            The dragon soared into the air and began to toss. He is now flying over the rift.
        </text>
        <path>80</path>
    </paragraph>
    <paragraph id="85" type="singlepath">
        <text>
           You have defeated the guard and you are nor leaving the chamber using the northern doors.
        </text>
        <path>75</path>
    </paragraph>
</gamebook>